Inventory of the Papers of Edwin S. Cohen
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- Private Practice and Law School Papers
  - Department of the Treasury News: oil, financial institutions, income taxes, etc., 1974-1975 (Box 123)
  - Effect on Revenue & Percent of Returns with Standard Deductions. For various changes in definition of itemized and standard deductions nationwide basis. AGI Group, 1967 (Box 123)
  - Estate Planning Conference. NYC Legacy Development Committee, United Jewish Appeal, 1973 (Box 123)
  - Estate Planning Seminar at Alma College, Mich., 1974 (Box 123)
  - Estate Planning Seminar, University of Richmond, 1976 (Box 123)
  - Federal Elections Campaign, 1974 (Box 124)
  - Federal Executive Institute Speech, 1973 (Box 124)
  - Federal Non-Recurring Forms 1000-7004, n.d. (Box 124)
  - Federal Tax Forms, 1942-1950, 1951-1954, 1956-1957, 4 folders (Box 125)
  - First Annual Estate Planning Seminar Speech, 1973 (Box 125)
  - Indiana Broadcasting Co. v. Commissioner of Internal revenue, 1965, 2 folders (Box 126)
  - IRS, Income Tax Regulations, Subchapter C, ESC comments, 1954-1955 (Box 126)
  - Irving Trust Company Lease Financing, 1959-1965 (Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 126)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1976 (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous Speech Materials, 1973-1974 (Box 127)
  - National Association of Investment Companies [NAIC] Regulations and Correspondence, 1955-1974 (Box 127)
  - NAIC-Deficit Corporations. Memoranda, correspondence and miscellaneous papers, 1952 (Box 127)
  - NAIC, Proposed Amendments to Internal Revenue Code concerning Long-Term Capital Gains of Regulated Investment Companies. Supplement Q. Drafts and memos to Treasury Department, 1952-1954, 2 folders (Box 127)
  - NAIC, Regulations, 1955 (Box 128)
  - National Association of Manufacturers. Panel on Taxation Committee, 1974 (Box 128)
  - NFL [National Football League]-AFL [American Football League] Constitution and By-Laws Drafts, 1970 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL, Drafts of Joint Agreement and Supplement Agreements, 1967 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL, Fiscal Agency Agreement Drafts, 1967 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL, Interim Constitution Drafts, 1967 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL, Merger: memoranda, notes, drafts, 1967-1968 (Box 128)
  - NFL-AFL, Constitution and By-Laws of NFL Miscellaneous Documents, 1967-1970, 2 folders (Box 129)
  - NFL-AFL, Miscellaneous Documents, 1967 (Box 129)
  - NFL-AFL, notes, statements, time and disbursements, 1967 (Box 129)
  - National Tax Association [NTA], Integration of the Corporate and Shareholder Income Tax, 1975 (Box 129)
  - Neu Foundation, Hugo and Doris, 1968 (Box 129)
  - Neu, Hugo Estate Plan, 1967-1968 (Box 129)
  - Neu, Hugo Index Files, n.d. (Box 130)
  - Neu, Hugo Miscellaneous Papers, 1968 (Box 130)
  - New York Bar Association: "Tax Revision, Rhetoric and Reality", 1974 (Box 130)
  - New York University Tax Institute, 27th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1968 (Box 130)
  - Pollack, Milton (World Trade Center Reports), 1965 (Box 130)
  - Pollack Industrial Corporation, 1963-1965 (Box 130)
  - Reserve City Bankers-NYC, Speech, 1974 (Box 131)
  - Steel Task Force. Summary of Steel Report, 1971 (Box 131)
  - Southeastern Association of Tax Administration, 1973 (Box 131)
  - United States Trust Company. Trust Provisions, Will Provisions, 1972 (Box 131)
  - United States Trust Company Speech, 1973 (Box 131)
  - University of Pennsylvania Tax Conference, 1974 (Box 131)
  - UVA Law School Miscellaneous Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 131)
  - UVA Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964-1979 (Box 131)
  - UVA, Will of Mr. Moyston. Financial Statements, Memoranda of Law, 1964-1965 (Box 132)
  - UVA, Will of Mr. Moyston Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 132)
  - Whitney re College Inn, 1965-1966 (Box 132)
  - Two cartons containing computer cards, some batches titled Penal Code, Virginia Constitution
- National Association of Investments Companies and Investment Company Institute
  - National Association of Investment Companies (NAIC) [2 folders], 1949-1962 (Box 133)
  - NAIC-Annual Reports, 1955-1958 (Box 133)
  - NAIC-Appreciated Assets Companies, 1956 (Box 133)
  - NAIC-"Attorney's Booklet". Tax Exemption-Audit for Fiscal Year, 1957-1961 (Box 133)
  - NAIC-Capital Gains Dividends Paid to Non Resident Aliens; Dividend Accrual; Ruling re Time of Accrual Dividends, 1945-1946 (Box 133)
  - NAIC-Constructive Distribution of Capital Gains, 1949-1957 (Box 134)
  - NAIC-Constructive Distribution of Capital Gains Drafts, 1952-1957 (Box 134)
  - NAIC-Constructive Distribution of Capital Gains Correspondence, 1944-1960, 3 folders (Box 134)
  - NAIC-Deductability of Stamp Tax, 1946-1958 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Documentary Stamp Tax-Unit Investment Trust, 1958-1964 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Effect of Legislative Activities, 1959-1969 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Estate and Gift Tax Valuation of Open-end Company Shares Drafts, 1956-1963 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Estate and Gift Tax Valuation of Open-end Company Shares. Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Excise Taxes. Excise Tax Technical Changes Commission Reports and Hearings, 1956-1958 (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Executive Committee Meetings Correspondence, 1954-1960, 2 folders (Box 135)
  - NAIC-Executive Committee Meetings Correspondence, 1954-1960, 2 folders (Box 136)
  - NAIC Extra Copies, 1952-1964, 3 folders (Box 136)
  - NAIC-Federal Documentary Stamp Taxes, 1956-1959 (Box 137)
  - NAIC-Federal Stamp Tax Amendments Correspondence, 1956 (Box 137)
  - NAIC-Federal Stamp Tax Correspondence, 1956-1965, 3 folders (Box 137)
  - NAIC-Federal Stamp Tax Correspondence, 1956-1965, 2 folders (Box 138)
  - NAIC General Correspondence, 1958-1962, 3 folders (Box 138)
  - NAIC General Correspondence, 1958-1962, 2 folders (Box 139)
  - NAIC-Hoffinger's Notes and Memos, 1950-1951 (Box 139)
  - NAIC-Individual Pension, 1959-1969, 2 folders (Box 139)
  - NAIC-Individual Pension, 1959-1969, 3 folders (Box 140)
  - NAIC-Individual Pensions Correspondence, 1953-1960, 2 folders (Box 140)
  - NAIC-Letter of February 10, 1959 to Lindsay. Drafts and exhibits, 1958-1959 (Box 141)
  - NAIC-Lobbying Activities, 1957-1962 (Box 141)
  - NAIC-ICI; Material dealing with proposed capital gains exemption for variable annuity reserves, 1962 (Box 141)
  - NAIC Memoranda, 1961-1962 (Box 141)
  - NAIC Mimeographed Copies, 1953-1956, 3 folders (Box 141)
  - NAIC-Municipal Bond Fund, 1954-1959, 3 folders (Box 142)
  - NAIC-New York State, 1952-1961 (Box 142)
  - NAIC-New Jersey Franchise Tax, 1953-1955 (Box 142)
  - NAIC-Optional Stock Dividends (Valuation under 1954 Code) Correspondence, 1954-1960 (Box 142)
  - NAIC-Pass Through of Foreign Tax Credit, 1954-1964 (Box 142)
  - NAIC-Real State Investment Trusts Correspondence. Prospectus of Trusts, 1958-1961 (Box 143)
  - NAIC-State Taxation of Capital Gains Dividends. American Business Shares. Selected American Shares, 1955-1956 (Box 143)
  - NAIC-State Taxation of Capital Gains Dividends. Chemical Fund. Massachusets Investors Growth Fund, 1954-1956 (Box 143)
  - NAIC-State Taxation of Capital Gains Dividends Correspondence, 1954-1966 (Box 143)
  - NAIC-State Taxation of Capital Gains Dividends. Group Securities, 1955-1956 (Box 143)
  - NAIC-State Taxation of Constructive Distribution of Capital Gains Correspondence, 1958 (Box 143)
  - NAIC Survey. Drafts, 1960-1961 (Box 143)
  - NAIC Survey, 1955-1960, 2 folders (Box 143)
  - NAIC Survey, 1955-1963, 2 folders (Box 144)
  - NAIC Texts and Pamphlets, 1957-1962 (Box 144)
  - NAIC-Variable Annuities. Drafts, 1955 (Box 144)
  - NAIC-Variable Annuities Correspondence and Extra Copies, 1954-1965, 2 folders (Box 144)
  - NAIC-Variable Annuities Correspondence and Extra Copies, 1954-1965, 2 folders (Box 145)
  - NAIC-Variable Annuities Statements and Memoranda, 1954-1955 (Box 145)
  - NAIC-Virginia License. Supreme Court Opinions, 1959 (Box 145)
  - NAIC-Withholding on Dividends. Clippings re Mr. Cohen statement, 1961-1962 (Box 145)
  - NAIC-Withholding on Dividends Correspondence (folder 1 of 2), 1960-1961 (Box 145)
  - NAIC-Withholding on Dividends Correspondence (folder 2 of 2), 1960-1961 (Box 146)
  - NAIC-Withholding on Dividends Legislation. Correspondence, 1950 (Box 146)
  - Investment Company Institute (ICI)-Account Numbers and Information. Miscellaneous Papers, 1961-1962 (Box 146)
  - ICI-Account Numbers and Information Reporting, 1960-1966, 2 folders (Box 146)
  - ICI-Amendments. Client Releases. Act of 1967, 1967-1968 (Box 146)
  - ICI-Annuities for Employees of Philantropies and Schools. Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 146)
  - ICI-Application to Internal Revenue Service for Determination Letter Approving Proposed Amendments to Retirement Plan for Self-Employed Individuals, 1965 (Box 146)
  - ICI-Average Cost Basis for Withdrawal Plans. Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 147)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds, 1964 (Box 147)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds. Blue Sky Memorandum, 1964 (Box 147)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds. Correspondence, 1961-1966, 2 folders (Box 147)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds Drafts, 1963-1965, 2 folders (Box 148)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds General Papers, 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 148)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds. Legislative History of the Glass-Steagall Act, 1965 (Box 148)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds Miscellaneous Papers, 1938-1963 (Box 148)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds Samples, 1962-1963 (Box 149)
  - ICI-Bank Common Trust Funds. Securities Acts Amendments of 1963, 1963 (Box 149)
  - ICI-Bills [lists], n.d. (Box 149)
  - ICI-Canada. Financial Statements of Canadian and South African Companies, 1959-1962, 2 folders (Box 149)
  - ICI-Canada Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 149)
  - ICI-Canada. Foreign Agents Registration, [1962] (Box 150)
  - ICI-re Canadian Investments Companies. Drafts, memoranda, correspondence, 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box 150)
  - ICI-Charitable Remainders. Correspondence, notes, drafts, 1965-1967 (Box 150)
  - ICI Correspondence, 1963-1970, 2 folders (Box 150)
  - ICI-David Silver-Vine, 1989 (Box 151)
  - ICI-Div. Reinv. Plans of Close-ends, 1954-1988, 2 folders (Box 151)
  - ICI-drafts, 1962 (Box 151)
  - ICI-Estate and Gift Tax Valuation of Open-end Co. Shares, correspondence, 1956-1962, 2 folders (Box 151)
  - ICI-Hardwick Testimony for 13 Foreign Investment Companies, 1962 (Box 151)
  - ICI-H.R. 8000-Interest Equalization Tax, 1963 (Box 151)
  - ICI-Indexing, 1985-1989 (Box 152)
  - ICI-Individual Pensions. Miscellaneous, 1956-1959 (Box 152)
  - ICI-IRA Savings, 1989 (Box 152)
  - ICI Miscellaneous, 1957-1961, 2 folders (Box 152)
  - ICI Miscellaneous Papers, 1963-1965, 2 folders (Box 153)
  - ICI Miscellaneous Papers, 1988-1990, 3 folders (Box 153)
  - ICI Miscellaneous Papers, 1988-1990, 2 folders (Box 154)
  - ICI-Multiple Class Close-end Funds, 1989 (Box 154)
  - ICI-Plans of Individual Pensions, 1963 (Box 154)
  - ICI-Prorating Ruling Request 3/14/1988, 1988 (Box 154)
  - ICI-Release File. News, bulletins, memos, 1959-1963, folder 1 of 3 (Box 154)
  - ICI-Release File. News, bulletins, memos, 1959-1963, folders 2 - 3 of 3 (Box 155)
  - ICI-Report on Study of Management Fees of Open-end Investment Companies, 1964-1966, 2 folders (Box 155)
  - ICI-Retirement Plan. Application to IRS for Determination Letter re Amendment of January 27, 1967, 1967, Bound File (Box 155)
  - ICI-Retirement Plan. Correspondence, clients papers, notes and drafts, 1968 (Box 155)
  - ICI-SEC (Securities and Exchange Commission) Advertising Rules, 1988 (Box 155)
  - ICI-State Taxation of Investment Companies and Underwriters, 1962 (Box 155)
  - ICI-Switching (Exchanges to Obtain Short-Term Capital Loss). Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 156)
  - ICI-TIAA-CREF, 1989, 2 folders (Box 156)
  - ICI-Valuations, [1965-1968] (Box 156)
  - ICI-Variable Annuities, 1964 (Box 156)
  - ICI Variable Annuities, 1980-1981 (Box 156)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends Drafts, 1962 (Box 156)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends General Correspondence, 1961-1963, 4 folders (Box 157)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends Legislation, 1959-1962 (Box 157)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends. Memoranda and intra-office correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends Newspaper Articles, 1962 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends. Public Statements and press releases, 1961-1962 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends. Statements by Members of Congress, 1962 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding on Dividends Statistical Data, 1959-1961 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding Tax on Interest and Dividends. Statements before House Ways and Means Committee, 1961 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding Tax on Interest and Dividends. Statements before Senate Committee (folder 1 of 2), 1962 (Box 158)
  - ICI-Withholding Tax on Interest and Dividends. Statements before Senate Committee (folder 2 of 2), 1962 (Box 159)
  - ICI-12(b) (1) Sales Charges, 1988-1989 (Box 159)
  - ICI-67 (c), 1987-1988 (Box 159)
  - ICI-401 (k)-Hardship Requests, 1988 (Box 159)
  - ICI-851 (g) (Designated Hedges), 1989 (Box 159)
  - ICI-852 (b) (3) (c)-Request for Reps. 10/10/1988, 1988 (Box 159)
  - ICI-852 (c)-Sam Thompson, 1989 (Box 159)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1984-1990, 2 folders (Box 159)
  - NYU Institute on Federal Taxation-Advisory Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 159)
  - New York Stock Exchange. Capital Gains Tax, 1963 (Box 160)
  - New York State Income Tax Study, 1959 (Box 160)
  - Sullivan & Cromwell (S & C) Miscellaneous Papers, 1949 (Box 160)
  - S & C: Broad St. Investing Co.; NAIC Miscellaneous; Investment Trust Group-Federal Taxes, 1941-1951 (Box 160)
  - S & C: Bullock Canadian Fund Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 160)
  - Thesis on Federal Taxation on Investment Companies, 1951-1953 (Box 160)
  - Ways and Means Committee General Tax Revision Bound File, 1959 (Box 160)
  - Ways and Means Committee General Tax Revision of 1959 Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 160)
  - Ways and Means Committee-General Tax Revision of 1959 Notes and Drafts, 1959 (Box 160)
  - United States of America before the Securities and Exchange Commission in the matter of The Prudential Insurance Company of America File No. 812-1386 (Investment Company Act of 1940), 1961 (Box 160)
  - Computer Statistical Data. (in shelves)
- Photographs
  - Brown, George Arthur [Director of the Bank of Jamaica], 1969
  - Cohen, Edwin S. as a young boy, n.d.
  - Cohen, Edwin S. [Libel Show?], n.d.
  - Cohen, Edwin S. with unidentified person [maybe David M. Fish?], 1973
  - Cohen, Edwin S. as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Tax Policy, 1970
  - Seaga, Edward Phillip George [Minister of Finance and Planning, Jamaica], 1969
  - Shearer, Hugh Lawson [Prime Minister of Jamaica], 1969